<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-21T02:46:08+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>The official website of the tech YouTuber StuffyXP!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Ubuntu Server experience.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/09/16/the-ubuntu-server-experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ubuntu Server experience." /><published>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/09/16/the-ubuntu-server-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/09/16/the-ubuntu-server-experience.html"><![CDATA[<p>Well i have gotten again into what is the Linux world, and oh well it was kind of a hassle, today i’ll be telling you my experience with the GNOME-less/GUI-less Ubuntu, known as Ubuntu Server.</p>

<h2 id="the-prologue">The Prologue</h2>

<p>You may ask why did i even did this, well basically after running out of space on my Xubuntu install (for the 2nd time), i decided to try something different, as uh, the Xubuntu Minimal install is particularly broken, i couldn’t even manage my own account!</p>

<p>My Linux distro of choice is Ubuntu Server, 22.04 Jammy Jellyfish (i can’t run 24.04 my system is not compatible okay), as Canonical said on their downloads website, and i quote: “It will not install a graphical user interface.”, interesting, huh, i thought to myself, as we’re Debian all of a sudden again! - jokes aside i was kinda curious about this, as i won’t have to deal with GNOME anymore, and just install my favorite Linux DE: XFCE!</p>

<p>I used Unetbootin to add the Linux image to the Windows Boot Manager, booted it up and worked like a charm, i even managed to not clean my disk by accident since GParted was not present! :D</p>

<p>All of that aside, something went wrong, no it didn’t error out when installing, it just didn’t recognize my network “”””"”card””””””, basically it was a network USB, a “Belkin Wireless G USB Network Adapter F5D7050” to be exact, it did detect my Ethernet cards (yes, <em>cards</em>, idk why does the eMachines ET1810 have two Ethernet cards), i didn’t really think about it and just did the installation as usual, and no, this does not look like the Debian installer , it looks more nice and friendly in my opinion, anyways everything went well and i was network-less, and oh boy i wouldn’t know how of much a problem that would be…</p>

<h2 id="the-problems">The problems</h2>

<p>Everybody encounters issues when trying new things, i’m no exception! (as always haha).</p>

<p>As said earlier, networking was one of those problems, i tried everything to make it work, searched up a tutorial on YT, and it actually worked, i was just kind of an idiot when doing so, it worked like a charm tho, if not this website wouldn’t exist, anyway here’s some highlights of the shenanigans i went through.</p>

<h3 id="ubuntu-cli-and-wi-fi">Ubuntu CLI and Wi-Fi</h3>

<p>First of all, i installed some packages from <a href="https://packages.ubuntu.com">the official Ubuntu packages website</a>, and unlike Microsoft, they actually had packages for older, unsupported releases! I went ahead and downloaded the WPA supplicant and some other dependencies, installed it and… no change, then i saw that you need to edit some .yml file located in “<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/etc/defualt/netplan</code>”, i opened it with GNU nano, and just added my device, configured it, added the SSID and password and used DHCP4, and it didn’t work… :/</p>

<p>It turned out that i edited the wrong file, i did it all again, and when i restarted it didn’t save for some reason, did it again and again for like 5 minutes, then in like the 16th time, i saw the verbose startup and …boom.. I saw “<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">197.168.0.24</code>” as the IP address and finally, i had been connected, i don’t know what i did but Ubuntu finally decided to accept the settings! i pinged www.google.com (as every PC user would do, i think) and i recieved 64 bytes as a reply!</p>

<p>With networking out of the way, i had another problem…</p>

<h3 id="the-xfcexorgx11-shenanigans">The XFCE/Xorg/X11 shenanigans</h3>

<p>The network configuration was done. Perfect. Now what?</p>

<p>Well i certainly not gonna use a command-line-interface for Linux the entire time so i went ahead and with my newly configured network, to install an X11 server!
I used <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">apt install (some command here i don't remember what installed x11 lmao)</code> to get up and running X11, execpt it didnt really work… then i decided to get <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">xubuntu-desktop</code> and it didnt work either, it opened but crashed on startup.</p>

<p>I saw a tutorial on how to get XFCE 4.16, ran the ansible-playbook (since it required it), but before that i got some files from that person’s website (the tutorial said so so don’t worry), i opened but required my SSH password… yeah i didn’t know how to get that…</p>

<p>I tried with my own user’s password, it didn’t work, i tried the root passowrd, it didn’t work either, at this point i didn’t know what else i could try so i just gave up, and no i didn’t delete the partition dw.</p>

<p>Then, after a restart (since i wanted to do show something funny on Windows, the pic below is what i wanted to show), then i rebooted back into Ubuntu and… i got what i wanted… almost.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-16/winpic.jpg" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" />
<em>Windows 7 Disk Management window letting me assign a letter, shrink and mount the Linux volume, which does not happen with other distros I had around (this did not happen with Xubuntu), prob happened since I first used that volume as FAT32 then used it in the installer so I wouldn’t get confused lmao</em></p>

<p>For some reason it installed GNOME instead of XFCE, i had a GUI, yay i guess, then everything went straightfoward, i opened the terminal, ran <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo apt install xfce4</code> and done, XFCE was installed, i just needed to make it the defualt session.</p>

<p>It took me a while on how to login into XFCE but then i just did and done! XFCE 4.16 was installed and worked like a charm!
Then i went on to customize the panels a bit, making the bottom one (where the launchers are located) to make a sort of a “macOS Dock”, and the top one where for everything else, workspaces, time &amp; date, user thingy, apps menu, window menu, etc.</p>

<p>Then i grabbed some apps, i got Firefox 130 and VS Code from Snap (ik everybody hates that but that’s the only way to get those apps okay?), grabbed Ruby-Lang from APT, installed Jekyll &amp; Bundler, and installed VMware 12 from <a href="https://softwareupdate.vmware.com/cds/vmw-desktop/ws/12.0.0/2985596/linux/core">here</a> and installed it, it worked, suprisingly!</p>

<p>And well, everything is done, here’s the end result!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-16/result.jpg" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Well after this rollercoaster of shenanigans, everything worked out, and i learned alot about Linux itself, that’s a win-win situation for me!
Now with a working development enviroment, expect more of this soon, new experiences, new shenanigans, new blog posts!</p>

<p>Oh, and also welcome to the new website! Have a great day!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well i have gotten again into what is the Linux world, and oh well it was kind of a hassle, today i’ll be telling you my experience with the GNOME-less/GUI-less Ubuntu, known as Ubuntu Server.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/blog/img/2024-09-16/preview.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/blog/img/2024-09-16/preview.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>