<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://stuffyxp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://stuffyxp.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-16T16:50:12-06:00</updated><id>https://stuffyxp.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">StuffyXP</title><subtitle>The official website of the tech YouTuber StuffyXP!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How Globed can save your Geometry Dash account</title><link href="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/12/15/how-globed-can-save-your-gd-account.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Globed can save your Geometry Dash account" /><published>2024-12-15T12:03:21-06:00</published><updated>2024-12-15T12:03:21-06:00</updated><id>https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/12/15/how-globed-can-save-your-gd-account</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/12/15/how-globed-can-save-your-gd-account.html"><![CDATA[<p>Ay’ up! So this might seem weird but this silly mod can actually save your GD account from being compromised.
How you may ask? Keep reading to found out!</p>

<h1 id="prologue">Prologue</h1>

<p>A few days ago i was playing Geometry Dash with other people via Globed, it’s basically 2.2’s delayed Versus mode made before RubRub even added it, then after going AFK for dinner, i came across the following message when coming back to my lappy…</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-12-15/globed-error.png" alt="" style="max-width: 100; height: auto;" />
Logged into my account in a different place?? What does that mean?</p>

<h1 id="the-hacking">The Hacking</h1>

<p>If you’ve been on the <strong>Minecraft</strong> community for a while, this may seem familiar to you.
<em>I was hacked.</em></p>

<p>Now, I was freaking out, i tried going into the <a href="https://www.boomlings.com/database/accounts/accountManagement.php">Account Management page</a> to try to change my password to no avail.</p>

<h2 id="how-did-i-notice">How did i notice?</h2>

<p>Well i’ll try to explain as best as i can.</p>

<p>When you use Globed for the first time, it will ask you if you agree for a bot to send you a message then delete it for aunthentication. If everything goes right, you’re in!</p>

<p>This method only happens locally, meaning that you will have to do it every single time you install Globed on a GD client, this does not transfer with Steam either.</p>

<p>Now, what happens when you aunthenticate on a new client while a client that already has an open session? (you may know the answer by now…)
It logs you out and let the new client in! Now it also gives you the prior warning that i showed you.</p>

<p>This is kinda similar to another incident in the Minecraft community, it just gives the same error as seen above.</p>

<h1 id="how-is-this-useful">How is this useful?</h1>

<p>By giving that warning, it advices you that someone else (a hacker) logged into your account, shoutout to the Globed team for adding this.</p>

<p>I emailed RobTop (<a href="mailto:support@robtopgames.com">via the support email</a>) about my compromised account not to found out a day later that i could reset my password via the previously mentioned account management page.
Which using that reset password method i should’ve changed my password for my main email as well-</p>

<p>Either way this is the end of this blog post, cya! ^^</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ay’ up! So this might seem weird but this silly mod can actually save your GD account from being compromised. How you may ask? Keep reading to found out!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/img/2024-12-15/thumb.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/img/2024-12-15/thumb.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to get Camtasia Recorder 8 working on Windows Vista</title><link href="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/09/28/how-to-get-camrec8-working-on-win-vista.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to get Camtasia Recorder 8 working on Windows Vista" /><published>2024-09-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-09-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/09/28/how-to-get-camrec8-working-on-win-vista</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/09/28/how-to-get-camrec8-working-on-win-vista.html"><![CDATA[<p>(<em>this is just a filler post as <a href="https://youtube.com/AzWtlbS2qJM">i uploaded a video today</a>, so why not give you guys some more stuffy content? :)</em>)</p>

<p>Ok so you’ve decided to get into video editng and YouTube video making and all that stuff with your good ol’ Windows Vista machine, great!!
<img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%201.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100; height: auto;" /></p>

<p>You chose Camtasia Studio as your video editor, which has A BUILT-IN RECORDER FOR YOUR SCREEN?!?!?!?
(ok it’s not that deep but okay)</p>

<p>And when you’re about to film your “”"”tutorial””””, you get greeted by this error…</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%202.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<p>Well today i’m gonna walkthrough you on how to fix this annoying error (side note: this only happens on Windows Vista no matter what Service Pack you’re in, and it <em>only</em> happen on Vista, XP, 7 and up do not have this problem…)</p>

<p>On the desktop, press on your keyboard the keys (oh wow the irony lmao) Win + R, this should open up</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%203.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<p>As you can see i already have that path written, but be sure to write that in in the run box: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">C:\Program Files (x86)\TechSmith\Camtasia Studio 8</code></p>

<p>After that, select the following program, double-click it and click “Properties”</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%204.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<p><em>image showing CamRecorder.exe being selected in Windows Explorer (sorry for the badly drawn arrow lmaooo)</em></p>

<p>After that, chose the “Compatibility” tab on the window and click “Show settings for all users” or smething similar (<em>sorry that it’s in Spanish i use(d to use) Spanish Windows…</em>)</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%205.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<p>Another window should open up, just tick the “Run this program as an administrator” checkbox, then click OK until you’re back to the Windows Explorer window</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%206.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<p>Then launch Camtasia Recorder as usual, and it should open up just fine, congratulations! you just fixed that one server referall error! :D</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-28/camrec8%207.JPG" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<p>Now just continue your recording and video editing as usual!</p>

<p><em>Note: Applying the compatibility settings under Windows XP SP2 may also work, but it’ll lack audio support when recording, so this is better if you are recording something audio focused or anything else related to audio.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[(this is just a filler post as i uploaded a video today, so why not give you guys some more stuffy content? :))]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/img/2024-09-28/thumb.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/img/2024-09-28/thumb.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ubuntu Server experience.</title><link href="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/09/16/the-ubuntu-server-experience.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ubuntu Server experience." /><published>2024-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2024-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/09/16/the-ubuntu-server-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/2024/09/16/the-ubuntu-server-experience.html"><![CDATA[<p>Well i have gotten again into what is the Linux world, and oh well it was kind of a hassle, today i’ll be telling you my experience with the GNOME-less/GUI-less Ubuntu, known as Ubuntu Server.</p>

<h2 id="the-prologue">The Prologue</h2>

<p>You may ask why did i even did this, well basically after running out of space on my Xubuntu install (for the 2nd time), i decided to try something different, as uh, the Xubuntu Minimal install is particularly broken, i couldn’t even manage my own account!</p>

<p>My Linux distro of choice is Ubuntu Server, 22.04 Jammy Jellyfish (i can’t run 24.04 my system is not compatible okay), as Canonical said on their downloads website, and i quote: “It will not install a graphical user interface.”, interesting, huh, i thought to myself, as we’re Debian all of a sudden again! - jokes aside i was kinda curious about this, as i won’t have to deal with GNOME anymore, and just install my favorite Linux DE: XFCE!</p>

<p>I used Unetbootin to add the Linux image to the Windows Boot Manager, booted it up and worked like a charm, i even managed to not clean my disk by accident since GParted was not present! :D</p>

<p>All of that aside, something went wrong, no it didn’t error out when installing, it just didn’t recognize my network “”””"”card””””””, basically it was a network USB, a “Belkin Wireless G USB Network Adapter F5D7050” to be exact, it did detect my Ethernet cards (yes, <em>cards</em>, idk why does the eMachines ET1810 have two Ethernet cards), i didn’t really think about it and just did the installation as usual, and no, this does not look like the Debian installer , it looks more nice and friendly in my opinion, anyways everything went well and i was network-less, and oh boy i wouldn’t know how of much a problem that would be…</p>

<h2 id="the-problems">The problems</h2>

<p>Everybody encounters issues when trying new things, i’m no exception! (as always haha).</p>

<p>As said earlier, networking was one of those problems, i tried everything to make it work, searched up a tutorial on YT, and it actually worked, i was just kind of an idiot when doing so, it worked like a charm tho, if not this website wouldn’t exist, anyway here’s some highlights of the shenanigans i went through.</p>

<h3 id="ubuntu-cli-and-wi-fi">Ubuntu CLI and Wi-Fi</h3>

<p>First of all, i installed some packages from <a href="https://packages.ubuntu.com">the official Ubuntu packages website</a>, and unlike Microsoft, they actually had packages for older, unsupported releases! I went ahead and downloaded the WPA supplicant and some other dependencies, installed it and… no change, then i saw that you need to edit some .yml file located in “<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/etc/defualt/netplan</code>”, i opened it with GNU nano, and just added my device, configured it, added the SSID and password and used DHCP4, and it didn’t work… :/</p>

<p>It turned out that i edited the wrong file, i did it all again, and when i restarted it didn’t save for some reason, did it again and again for like 5 minutes, then in like the 16th time, i saw the verbose startup and …boom.. I saw “<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">197.168.0.24</code>” as the IP address and finally, i had been connected, i don’t know what i did but Ubuntu finally decided to accept the settings! i pinged www.google.com (as every PC user would do, i think) and i recieved 64 bytes as a reply!</p>

<p>With networking out of the way, i had another problem…</p>

<h3 id="the-xfcexorgx11-shenanigans">The XFCE/Xorg/X11 shenanigans</h3>

<p>The network configuration was done. Perfect. Now what?</p>

<p>Well i certainly not gonna use a command-line-interface for Linux the entire time so i went ahead and with my newly configured network, to install an X11 server!
I used <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">apt install (some command here i don't remember what installed x11 lmao)</code> to get up and running X11, execpt it didnt really work… then i decided to get <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">xubuntu-desktop</code> and it didnt work either, it opened but crashed on startup.</p>

<p>I saw a tutorial on how to get XFCE 4.16, ran the ansible-playbook (since it required it), but before that i got some files from that person’s website (the tutorial said so so don’t worry), i opened but required my SSH password… yeah i didn’t know how to get that…</p>

<p>I tried with my own user’s password, it didn’t work, i tried the root passowrd, it didn’t work either, at this point i didn’t know what else i could try so i just gave up, and no i didn’t delete the partition dw.</p>

<p>Then, after a restart (since i wanted to do show something funny on Windows, the pic below is what i wanted to show), then i rebooted back into Ubuntu and… i got what i wanted… almost.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-16/winpic.jpg" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" />
<em>Windows 7 Disk Management window letting me assign a letter, shrink and mount the Linux volume, which does not happen with other distros I had around (this did not happen with Xubuntu), prob happened since I first used that volume as FAT32 then used it in the installer so I wouldn’t get confused lmao</em></p>

<p>For some reason it installed GNOME instead of XFCE, i had a GUI, yay i guess, then everything went straightfoward, i opened the terminal, ran <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo apt install xfce4</code> and done, XFCE was installed, i just needed to make it the defualt session.</p>

<p>It took me a while on how to login into XFCE but then i just did and done! XFCE 4.16 was installed and worked like a charm!
Then i went on to customize the panels a bit, making the bottom one (where the launchers are located) to make a sort of a “macOS Dock”, and the top one where for everything else, workspaces, time &amp; date, user thingy, apps menu, window menu, etc.</p>

<p>Then i grabbed some apps, i got Firefox 130 and VS Code from Snap (ik everybody hates that but that’s the only way to get those apps okay?), grabbed Ruby-Lang from APT, installed Jekyll &amp; Bundler, and installed VMware 12 from <a href="https://softwareupdate.vmware.com/cds/vmw-desktop/ws/12.0.0/2985596/linux/core">here</a> and installed it, it worked, suprisingly!</p>

<p>And well, everything is done, here’s the end result!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/img/2024-09-16/result.jpg" alt="" style="max-width: 100%; height: auto;" /></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Well after this rollercoaster of shenanigans, everything worked out, and i learned alot about Linux itself, that’s a win-win situation for me!
Now with a working development enviroment, expect more of this soon, new experiences, new shenanigans, new blog posts!</p>

<p>Oh, and also welcome to the new website! Have a great day!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well i have gotten again into what is the Linux world, and oh well it was kind of a hassle, today i’ll be telling you my experience with the GNOME-less/GUI-less Ubuntu, known as Ubuntu Server.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/img/2024-09-16/thumb.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://stuffyxp.github.io/blog/img/2024-09-16/thumb.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>